A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Grants O-R FA732F
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Ford Foundation Grants - O to R, 1941-2010
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (08750414), 1987 February 01-1988 September 01 (Reel R5816)
    Feasibility study on development of an associate arts degree in immigration paralegal studies
    Rights And Social Justice Program [RSJ]; Education & Culture Program [EC]
    Bernstein, Alison R.; McClymont, Mary (Mary E.)
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (08800760), 1988 July 01-1990 July 31 (Reel R6188)
    Partial support for a conference on "comparative politics:research perspectives for the next twenty years"
    Heginbotham, Stanley J. (Stanely Jay); Stanley, Peter W.
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (08800868), 1988 August 01-1995 December 31 (Reel R7271)
    General support for the inter-university program for latino research (iup)
    $2,629,600.00; $2,629,600.00
    United States; Hispanic Americans
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (08801169), 1988 October 01-1991 December 30 (Reel R6272)
    Support for a new phase of work on improving transfer opportunities for community college students.
    $100,000.00; $93,701.16
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (08900470), 1989 June 01-1993 June 30 (Reel R6406)
    Grant to mainstream new research on minority women into undergraduate liberal arts curricula
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (08900624), 1989 September 01-1995 August 31 (Reel R7318)
    Support to enable the ralph bunche institute to expand educational opportunities for minority students and to hold a conference.
    $241,500.00; $241,500.00
    Forman, Shepard; Romero, Anthony D.
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (08901310), 1989 September 01-1993 June 30 (Reel R7893)
    Support for demonstration projects to increase minority students access to college and college teaching careers
    Bernstein, Alison R.; Beckham, Edgar F.
    New York (State); Northeastern States
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (08903015), 1989 September 01-1993 December 31 (Reel R6679)
    Support for project to provide curriculum and materials for immigration paralegal training programs
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09050785), 1990 May 01-1991 May 01 (Reel R6173, Reel R6441)
    Costs of caribbean, brazilian and philippine participants attending the 4th international interdisciplinary congress on women
    Indonesia (Jakarta); Latin America & The Caribbean [LAC]; Brazil (Rio de Janeiro)
    Nichols, Rebecca; Posada, Carmen; Reichmann, Rebecca Lynn
    Brazil; Philippines; West Indies
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09051068), 1990 July 01-1991 December 01 (Reel R6127)
    Support for a collaborative model for reproductive rights education among college undergraduates (rhg)
    Stanley, Peter W.; Zeitlin, June H.
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09051194), 1990 June 01-1991 November 30 (Reel R6168)
    Planning and evaluation of an urban summit of mayors of large u.s. Cities
    $50,000.00; $25,591.34
    Arnold, David D.; Curvin, Robert
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09100971), 1991 September 01-1994 August 31 (Reel R6664)
    Support for legal research & publications on international women's rights and human rights
    $65,000.00; $64,137.69
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09151069), 1991 September 01-1992 September 30 (Reel R6282)
    To help cuny's alt. Baccalaureate degree program developo ways for former community college students to complete bachelor's degrees
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09200420), 1992 January 01-1997 March 31 (Reel R7357)
    Planning the hunter college reproductive rights education project for an international research network on reproductive rights (rhg)
    Rights And Social Justice Program [RSJ]; Reproductive Health And Population Program [RHP]
    $418,000.00; $418,000.00
    Hempel, Margaret L.; Zeitlin, June H.
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09300576), 1993 April 01-1999 June 30 (Reel R8389)
    To assist the bronx's educational alliance to create interschool networks to facilitate academic progress of disadvantaged students
    Bronx (New York, N.Y.); New York (N.Y.)
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09301183), 1993 September 01-1998 October 31 (Reel R6926)
    Support for the queens urban partnership program's work to assist students who are at risk to succeed in the borough's schools
    $710,000.00; $710,000.00
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09301270), 1993 September 01-1995 December 31 (Reel R7939)
    Support for completion of "who built america?" video series & planning for nationwide expansion of high school/college collaboration
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09350188), 1992 November 01-1995 December 31 (Reel R7297)
    For a seminar series on the impact of research concerning gender, race, ethnicity and class on four traditional academic disciplines
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09350568), 1992 December 01-1994 November 30 (Reel R6907)
    Partial support for a study of inter-group relations in new york city
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09351113), 1993 June 01-1994 October 01 (Reel R6871)
    Supplemental support for a seminar on equity and school finance reform
    Bernstein, Alison R.; Petrovich, Janice
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09401248), 1994 September 01-1999 June 30 (Reel R8414)
    Support for a seminar series on issues of concern to caribbean populations in the islands and in new york
    Eguizabal, Cristina; Lynch, Barbara D.; Romero, Anthony D.
    New York (State); West Indies
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09550200), 1994 October 01-1996 October 31 (Reel R7103)
    Support for research on civil rights issues and the application of international human rights law to domestic advocacy efforts
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09550245), 1994 November 01-1995 April 30 (Reel R6941)
    Travel support for participants from u.s. & abroad to attend an international conf. On "the global society and the latino community"
    United States; Latin America
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09550365), 1995 January 01-1995 December 31 (Reel R6922)
    Support for a comparative study of state education reform and its impact on large urban school districts
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09550481), 1995 February 15-1995 December 31 (Reel R6909)
    Support for documenting a conference on lesbian and gay sexualities in the african diaspora
    $50,000.00; $47,463.99
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09550596), 1994 November 01-1996 January 31 (Reel R7257, Reel R7351, Reel R7989, Reel R8659)
    Support for nigeria country team reproductive rights activities related to the 1995 un fourth world conference on women
    $69,000.00; $68,314.50
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09550827), 1995 March 01-1995 November 30 (Reel R6827)
    Support for the howard samuels state management and policy center to develop a study on community development organizations
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09551470), 1995 October 01-1997 May 01 (Reel R7268)
    Dissem. Of info. Produced by seminar series examining impact of research concerning diversity on seven traditional academic disciplines
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09600442), 1996 March 01-1998 February 28 (Reel R7515, Reel R8504)
    Support for a multi-state study and seminar on state politics of urban school reform
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09601045), 1996 July 01-2002 June 30 (Reel R9245)
    Support for community-higher education partnership initiative in south african tertiary institutions
    Southern Africa (Johannesburg); Education & Culture Program [EC]; KC & F - Office of the Vice President
    Bawa, Ahmed; Zwerling, L. Steven
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09651204), 1996 August 01-1998 April 30 (Reel R7903)
    Partial support for the development of a public information project on the theme of diversity at the city college of new york
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09700303), 1997 January 01-2002 June 30 (Reel R8947)
    To enable the national center for urban partnerships to disseminate lessons from the 16-city program (870-1005)
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09701499), 1997 September 01-1999 June 30 (Reel R8502)
    United States; Latin America; West Indies
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09701526), 1997 July 01-1999 June 30 (Reel R8299)
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09701782), 1997 September 01-2000 March 31 (Reel R8469)
    Support for health force: women and men against aids to develop and implement a muslim hiv/aids initiative
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09800377), 1998 January 01-2001 September 30 (Reel R9209)
    To enable the national center for urban partnerships to continue to coordinate the 16-city urban partnership program (870-1005)
    $2,010,000.00; $2,010,000.00
    United States; Educational change -- United States; Educational equalization -- United States
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09800945), 1998 March 01-2000 June 30 (Reel R8614)
    Support for a multi-state study on urban school reform
    United States; Public schools--United States--Reform; Educational change -- United States
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09801076), 1998 April 01-2002 August 31 (Reel R9208)
    To help support the first major national and interdenominational study of hispanic religious issues in the u.s.
    Education, Sexuality, Religion; Community and Resource Development; Human Rights
    $660,100.00; $660,100.00
    Buchanan, Constance H.; Davie, Fred A.; Eguizabal, Cristina
    United States; West Indies; Global; Religion--Study and teaching--United States
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09801249), 1998 May 01-2002 June 30 (Reel R8993)
    Support for evaluation of educational quality enhancement programs in four latin american countries
    Mexico and Central America (Mexico City); Andean Region and Southern Cone (Santiago); KC & F - Office of the Vice President; Brazil (Rio de Janeiro); Education, Sexuality, Religion
    Brooke, Nigel P.; Palacios, Maria Amelia; Martin, Christopher J. (Christopher James); Petrovich, Janice
    Latin America; Education, Primary -- Latin America; Educational change -- Latin America
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09801400), 1998 July 01-2002 June 30 (Reel R8945)
    Supplemental funding for the bronx educational alliance's school reform work (0930-0576)
    New York (State); Educational change -- New York (State) -- New York (State)
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09801664), 1998 May 01-2001 June 01 (Reel R8907)
    Partial support for a study of the spatial mismatch hypothesis
    $47,000.00; $47,000.00
    United States; Pay equity--United States; African Americans -- Employment -- United States
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09850758), 1998 February 01-1999 January 31 (Reel R8374)
    Support for the planning of a conference on women, race, ethnicity and international human rights
    $53,000.00; $50,894.15
    Global; Latin America; Human rights advocacy -- Congresses; Race relations--Congresses; Women's rights--Congresses
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09900400), 1999 February 01-2000 October 31 (Reel R8523)
    Support for a project on the intersection of international human rights law & gender, race & ethnic discrimination
    Brazil (Rio de Janeiro); Mexico and Central America (Mexico City); Andean Region and Southern Cone (Santiago); PSJ - Office of the Vice President; Human Rights
    Atkin, Lucille C.; Jenkins, Alan; Ore Aguilar, Gaby; Phillips, Barbara; Telles, Edward Eric
    United States; Latin America; Human rights -- Latin America -- Congresses; Women's rights--Latin America--Congresses
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09900562), 1999 January 01-2000 December 31 (Reel R8681)
    Disseminate lessons from foundation education reform initiatives in conjunction with department of education's gear up initiative
    $1,042,000.00; $1,042,000.00
    United States; Educational equalization -- United States; Minority college students--United States
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (09900985), 1999 June 01-2002 December 31 (Reel R9187)
    Partial support for "latinas in the united states: an historical encyclopedia"
    United States; Hispanic American women--Study and teaching -- United States; Hispanic American women -- United States -- History -- Encyclopedias
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (10001419), 2000 July 01-2003 July 31 (Reel R9160)
    To study how historically black colleges, universities, and african-american churches have used cdc's to revitalize distressed communities
    $257,500.00; $257,500.00
    Garcia, Miguel; Gilbert, Linetta
    United States; African Americans; Church and social problems -- United States; Community and college -- United States; Community development corporations -- Research -- United States; Urban renewal--United States
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (10002009), 2000 September 01-2002 September 30 (Reel R9278)
    Partial support for research and analysis on the relationship between civic engagement, and access and equity in schools worldwide
    $535,000.00; $535,000.00
    United States; Global; Educational change -- United States; Community and school -- United States; Civil society -- United States -- Citizen participation
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (10050531), 2000 February 01-2001 January 31 (Reel R8872)
    Support for a conference of the nigerian diaspora on "preventing the breakdown of democracy in nigeria: strategies for a 'living' popular constitution"
    Nigeria; Constitutional Law --Nigeria; Civil society -- Nigeria -- Citizen participation; Democracy -- Nigeria
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (10050761), 2000 January 01-2002 December 31 (Reel R9149)
    Support for an evaluation of the effectiveness of constituency building for africa undertaken by the national summit on africa process
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (10051795), 2000 July 01-2004 August 31 (Reel R9163)
    Support for educational outreach and advocacy on behalf of Afro-Latinos
    United States; North America; Latin America; West Indies; African Americans -- Study and teaching -- Caribbean Region; Afro-Caribbeans -- Study and teaching; Afro-Latinos -- Study and teaching
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (10101795), 2001 July 01-2003 June 30 (Reel R9122)
    For the Center for the Study of Philanthropy to conduct research on patterns of giving within communities of color and among women in New York City
    United States; New York (State); Humanitarianism--United States; Social Justice--United States
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (10150573), 2001 February 01-2002 April 30 (Reel R9163)
    Support for the Center for Puerto Rican Studies' National Latino Education Research Agenda Project
    $47,300.00; $47,300.00
    United States; Hispanic Americans -- Education -- Research; Educational equalization -- United States
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (10151940), 2001 June 01-2002 May 31 (Reel R8981)
    For a monograph on Sunset Park, a Latino and Asian immigrant neighborhood, including recommendations for strategies to promote sustainable and equitable revitalization
    $35,000.00; $34,998.22
    Tonga; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Immigrants -- New York (State)
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (10250381), 2002 January 01-2002 August 31 (Reel R9018)
    For research to provide historical mapping of the public interest in media policy and technology
    United States; Mass media policy--United States--Citizen participation
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (10251891), 2002 September 01-2003 October 31 (Reel R9230)
    To hire a professional archivist for the Historical Archives of the Puerto Rican Migration
    Media Arts and Culture; Education, Sexuality, Religion
    Pwono, Damien M.; Petrovich, Janice
  - Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY) (10300421), 2003 January 01-2004 June 30 (Reel R9078)
    For an evaluation of philanthropic efforts in support of social justice community organizing
  - Research Group Nanduti (08950405), 1989 February 15-1989 August 15 (Reel R6291, Reel R6451)
    Research and publications on contemporary political and social issues in paraguay
  - Research Institute "Dr. Jose Maria Luis Mora" (10450836), 2004 July 01-2005 March 31 (Reel R9205)
    To fund internships for graduates of its master's program in international cooperation for development & establish a development philanthropy and international cooperation jobs clearinghouse
    $31,116.26; $31,116.26
  - Research Institute For Educational Problems, Inc. (07300427), 1973 April 16-1974 September 30 (Reel R2368, Reel R2369)
    Preparation & completion of a book based on longitudinal study of black adolescents (pathways project) directed by dr. R. Rosenthal
    $82,193.00; $82,193.00
    Lynch, Barbara D.; Martus, Marjorie
  - Research Institute For Peace And Security (07950559), 1979 April 01-1980 March 31 (Reel R4317, Reel R5341)
    Partial support for producing an asian strategic survey
    Japan
    $18,433.00; $18,433.00
  - Research Institute for Peace and Security (08000527), 1980 June 01-1984 May 31 (Reel R4402)
    Support for research and editing "asian security"
  - Research Institute for Peace and Security (08350918), 1983 September 01-1991 March 31 (Reel R6002)
    Partial support for editorial assistance for "asian security"
    $51,179.00; $51,179.00
  - Research Institute for Peace and Security (08400424), 1984 April 01-1994 March 31 (Reel R6648)
    Partial support for a training program in international security and arms control for japanese scholars
    $489,980.00; $489,980.00
  - Research Institute for Peace and Security (09001219), 1990 October 01-1993 September 30 (Reel R6948)
    Support for a project on "regional approach to confidence and security building in the far east"
    $266,900.00; $266,900.00
  - Research Institute For The Study Of Man (06600199), 1966 May 06-1969 May 05 (Reel R4105, Reel R4106)
    Graduate field training in the caribbean for north american and west indian students
  - Research Institute For The Study Of Man (06800024), 1967 November 03-1968 November 02 (Reel R1872)
    Conference on research and resources of haiti
    $12,500.00; $11,408.00
  - Research Institute for the Study of Man (08450744), 1984 August 01-1985 January 31 (Reel R5186)
    Support for participation by academics from the english-speaking caribbean in a conference on caribbean studies
  - Research Libraries Group (08000701), 1980 August 01-1984 August 31 (Reel R4832)
    Development of computer input capacity of east asian scripts for library bibliographic use
  - Research Libraries Group (08601096), 1986 October 01-1989 March 31 (Reel R5581)
    To provide support to improve the performance of the interlibrary loan system
    $250,475.00; $250,475.00
  - Research Libraries Group (09900984), 1999 June 01-2003 June 30 (Reel R9144)
    For the Cultural Media Initiative, a collaborative effort to use digital technology to improve access to the material culture collections of libraries, archives and museums
    Global; Research libraries--Global; Library materials--Digitization--Global; Archival materials -- Digitization -- Global
  - Research Support Fund (10001680), 2000 July 01-2003 June 30 (Reel R9022)
    Activities to sharpen and strengthen asset-building strategies related to natural capital assets in the united states
    Global; Conservation of natural resources -- Citizen participation; Environmental law; Sustainable development--Citizen participation
  - Research Support Fund (10101245), 2001 May 01-2003 April 30 (Reel R9206)
    For an international conference on asset-building strategies as applied to natural assets
    Global; Conservation of natural resources -- Global -- Congresses; Development economics -- Global -- Congresses; Sustainable development--Global--Congresses
  - Research, Planning and Evaluation Center (09951620), 1999 August 01-2000 July 31 (Reel R8273)
    Strengthen the capacity and influence of honduran civil society in post-mitch hurricane reconstruction supporting the promotion of effective civic participation at the municipal & national levels
    Brown, Kimberli R.; Faulhaber, Ingrid S.
    Central America; Natural disasters--Honduras; Municipal government--Honduras--Citizen participation; Hurricane Mitch, 1998
  - Reserve Bank of Zimbabwe (09000833), 1990 May 01-1995 September 30 (Reel R6771, Reel R7052, Reel R7053, Reel R7229)
    Support for the central bank's research and staff training program
    Chege, Michael; Lopez, Jose Gabriel
  - Resident Advisory Board Of Philadelphia (07100430), 1971 July 30-1974 June 30 (Reel R2798)
    Operating support for rab's low income public housing activities
    Gault, Ronald T.; McDonald, Bernard
  - Residents' Association of Plataforma (08250438), 1982 January 05-1982 April 04 (Reel R3365, Reel R5560)
    Support for the association's members to participate in first con-gress of the national federation of local residents' association
    $3,130.00; $3,130.00
  - Residents' Association of Plataforma (08250658), 1982 February 15-1984 February 14 (Reel R5256, Reel R5560)
    Partial support for a community program of infant child care and pre-school education
    $51,200.00; $51,200.00
  - Residents' Association of Plataforma (08550916), 1984 November 01-1986 June 26 (Reel R5903)
    Support for a community infant care and kindergarten program in salvador (brazil)
  - Resolution, Inc. (07950314), 1979 April 01-1979 September 30 (Reel R2708)
    Partial support for development of materials to accompany their film, "we've always done it this way"
    $4,900.00; $4,900.00
  - Resolution, Inc. (08150047), 1980 November 01-1981 January 31 (Reel R2976)
    Partial support for the transfer of "the detroit model" program of"bill moyer's journal" from videotape to film
  - Resolution, Inc. (08550403), 1985 May 06-1985 November 05 (Reel R5915)
    Support for importing three films on south africa and for printing and distribution of an informational booklet describing them
    $15,936.00; $15,936.00
  - Resolution, Inc. (09150461), 1991 February 27-1992 February 26 (Reel R6128)